The peak of Mount Qomolangma, 8,849 meters above sea level.
珠穆朗玛峰峰顶，海拔8849米。
Chimborazo, 6,263 m; Mont Blanc, 4,806 m; Pradidali hut, at the foot of the Pala group in the Dolomites, 2,278 m.
钦博拉索山，6263米；勃朗峰，4806米；位于多洛米蒂山脉帕拉山群脚下的普拉迪达利小屋，2278米。
It is common practice to provide the elevation of a place.
标出一个地方的海拔高度是一种常见做法。
Simple readings are now readily available on our phones and wearables.
如今，在手机和可穿戴设备上就能轻松获取简单的读数。
But elevation is necessarily relative: only the choice of a reference point allows us to express numerically the height of an object or a location.
但海拔必然是相对的：只有选定一个参照点，我们才能用数字表示某个物体或地点的高度。
The idea of sea level as a reference point for elevations has by now been around for so long as to go essentially unnoticed — we mention it without even considering what it means.
把海平面作为海拔参照点的观念由来已久，以至于基本上没人注意到它——我们提到它时，甚至都不会去想它意味着什么。
That the concept has a history is easily ignored.
这个概念有它自己的历史，这一点很容易被忽视。
We tend to forget that sea level is a product of technically and culturally determined assumptions.
我们往往会忘记，海平面是由技术和文化所决定的种种假设的产物。
In this book, I tell a story of these assumptions.
在这本书中，我讲述的就是这些假设的故事。
Appropriately, the book took shape during a summer spent between sea and mountains.
恰如其分的是，这本书是在一个往返于大海与群山之间的夏天里成形的。
A month after visiting the French Riviera and enjoying the sandy beaches of Nice and Menton, I went hiking with friends in the Pala group.
在游览法国里维埃拉、享受了尼斯和芒通的沙滩一个月后，我和朋友们去帕拉山群徒步。
Resting on a pass near the Pradidali hut, we began discussing the readings offered by our altimeters.
在普拉迪达利小屋附近的一处山口休息时，我们开始讨论各自测高仪给出的读数。
Why did they vary ever so slightly from one instrument to the next?
为什么不同仪器之间的读数会有那么一丁点差异呢？
This sense of uncertainty led me to think about the meaning of zero.
这种不确定感促使我思考“零”的含义。
This is how I began my search for the conceptual history of sea level.
我就是这样开始探寻海平面这一概念的历史的。
In this book I examine three crucial stages in the history of mean sea level.
在本书中，我考察了平均海平面历史上的三个关键阶段。
These stages mirror the development of human conceptions of the sea.
这些阶段反映了人类对海洋认识的发展。
Since I began thinking about this project in August 2011, the issue of sea-level rise and the need to place it historically have only become more urgent: between then and the end of 2022 the global sea rose by almost 5 centimeters, about half of the overall rise recorded by satellites since 1993.
自2011年8月我开始构思这个项目以来，海平面上升问题以及从历史角度看待它的必要性都变得愈发紧迫：从那时到2022年底，全球海平面上升了近5厘米，约为1993年以来卫星记录的总上升幅度的一半。